Hello, Statistic body. I'm yoga. Welcome to
competition. All statistic subject. Okay, in this
section I will tell you about data collection, the
objectives off the session, our definition off data types
, off data primary and secondary data and the last
IHS data collection techniques. Okay, Now I start
from definition off data, as we know from the
previous chapter that statistics is important and closely related to
data. Now, I will explain about the definition
off data itself. In definition one, data are
plain facts usually roll numbers and in the definition to
data are individual pieces off, factual information recorded and
used for the purpose off analysis. So from the
two definitions, we know that data is the part
off information. Now, I will explain about types
off data data is divided into two kinds, namely
qualitative and quantitative. Qualitative data itself is divided into
nominal and or denial for quantitative is defected into inter
file and rescue each off. The inter fall and
rescue have discrete data and continuous data. Okay,
Now I will explain more detail about the types off
data. Qualitative. Okay. Qualitative is a data
concerned with descriptions which can be observed but cannot be
computed. And as we know, that qualitative data
is divided into nominal an orginal scale. No,
I will explain about the nominal scale nominal scale called
simply because levels you can check the examples below to
understand what the nominal is now for the orginal scale
, the orginal scale have order off the values.
The order is important and significant, but the differences
between each one is not really known. And you
can see the example below. Okay. Now its
quantitative quantitative is the one that focus on numbers and
mathematical calculations and can be calculated and computed and quantitative
. Uh huh. Toe rescue. The first is
interval scale and interval skills are numbering skills in which
we know both the order and the exact differences between
the values and second is ratio skills. Raise your
skills are data measurement skills because they tell us about
the order. They tell us the exact value between
units, and they also have a new absolute zero
, which allows for a wide range off both descriptive
and inferential statistics to be applied now I will explain
about discrete and continuous data for discrete data can only
take certain values. And that's the example, the
number off student and the number that appear after you
rolling dies and continuous data for continuous data can take
any value within a range. And the examples are
the first is a person's hey and then the time
in a race. And then a talks waked and
the length off a leaf. No, If there's
a question how we to get the data, the
answer is they're too option to get data. First
is get the data by ourselves. For example,
a researcher conduct some research, and he gathered the
data by himself. We called the data as primary
data. Second is Katie data from another source.
For example, I collect the data from Internet or
I ask my fellow researcher to give his data.
The data that I get is called secondary data,
and there are many techniques to get the data.
But in this session I only mentioned five techniques,
namely, record station senses, survey experiment and observation
. Registration is a method which in places more on
structured recording through various institutions, and census is a
complete way off collecting data where all elements in the
population that are object off the research are investigated or
enumerated one by one. And then the next ISS
survey survey is collecting information from a sample group to
learn about the entire population and next ISS experiment.
An experimental study has the researcher purposely attempting to influence
the result. The goal is to do their mind
what effect a particular treatment has on the outcome.
Researchers take measurements or surface off the sample population,
and you can read the example below. No,
the observational in the observational study, the simple population
being studied ISS miserable or surveilled as it ISS.
The researcher observes the subjects and missiles variables but doesn't
influence the population in any way or attempt to intervene
in the study. There is no manipulation by the
researcher, and the last is that those that we
can use to collect the data. You can use
questionnaire in their view checklist or any digital tools.
Okay, I think enough for the session. I
hope you enjoy that. And CIA